travelpulse.com 2013-10-19

# Terms of Use

## Privacy Policy

**travAlliancemedia, LLC** **  
Internet Privacy Policy**

_**UPDATED AS OF** **April 22,2013**_

travAlliancemedia, LLC ("TAM") publishes this Internet Privacy Policy to inform you of our practices concerning the collection and use of information you provide us through interactions with this website and the other TAM-affiliated websites and all TAM publications. This policy is not applicable to information gathered by other methods or controlled by other agreements. 

**How We Collect Information**

TAM collects personal information in a variety of ways, including when you register with TAM on this website, when you subscribe to TAM services through this website, when you use TAM products or services via the website, when you visit TAM websites or the websites of certain TAM partners, and when you enter Internet-based promotions or sweepstakes sponsored or administered by TAM.

_User Registration_

When you register on our website, we ask for and collect information such as your name, email address, birth date, gender, zip code, occupation, and industry. For some products and services we may also ask for your address and information about you or your businessï¿½s assets or income. Once you register with TAM and sign in to our services, you are not anonymous to us.

_e-letters_

Users may elect to participate in a variety of TAM e-letters (email services), ranging from daily news to supplier hot specials. TAM collects personal information in connection with the registration for and use of such services.

_Contests_

Users may elect to participate in promotions and/or promotional contests that TAM conducts from time to time on behalf of its clients. TAM collects personal information in connection with user registration for and participation in such promotions and contests.  

_Educational Programs and Seminars_

Users may elect to participate in educational programs and seminars that TAM conducts from time to time. TAM collects personal information in connection with user registration for and participation in such programs.  

_Cookies_

"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computerï¿½s hard drive. TAM or its advertisers may send a cookie to your computer through your browser. TAM uses cookies to track page requests and the duration of each userï¿½s visit and the use of cookies allows us to provide a userï¿½s browser with information tailored to the visitor's preferences and needs and to also streamline the userï¿½s visits to our website. You can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings of your browser. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or allow your browser to show you when a cookie is being sent. If you choose not to accept cookies, your experience at our website and other websites may be diminished and some features may not work as intended. 

_IP Addresses_

TAM automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, TAM cookie information, and the website page you request. TAM uses this information to help diagnose problems with our servers, for system administration, and to examine our website traffic in aggregate.  The information may be collected and used to improve the content of our Web pages and to customize content and/or layout for each user.  

_Purchases_

If you are purchasing something from an TAM website, we need to know personally identifiable information such as your name, email address, mailing address, credit card number, and expiration date. This allows us to process and fulfill your order and to notify you of your order status. This information may also be used by TAM to notify you of related products and services. Credit card information will not be shared or sold to unaffiliated third parties for any purpose without your express permission, except as necessary to process the transaction. 

**Use of Information**

If you elect to provide us personal information, we use it primarily to deliver the service you requested. TAM may use personal information in a variety of ways including the following:

  * TAM may use personal information to collected through its website to send out targeted email promotions on behalf of its advertisers and industry partners.  

  * TAM may combine information about you that we have with information we obtain from business partners or other companies in order to better deliver products and services that may be of interest and benefit to you.  

  * TAM may use personal information to contact users regarding renewing subscriptions to TAM services and products.  

  * TAM may use personally identifiable information to send notification of TAM's or our partnersï¿½ products and services by such methods as email and/or postal mail.  

  * If you provide financial information, we use that information primarily to verify your credit and collect payments for your purchases, orders, subscriptions, etc.  

  * TAM may send product announcements or special edition e-letters to online registrants.  

  * If you participate in an TAM educational program, seminar, or other time-sensitive program, we may contact you to remind you of upcoming deadlines or additional information concerning these programs.  

  * TAM occasionally conducts subscriber and/or user surveys to better target our content to our audiences. The aggregated information collected is sometimes shared with our advertisers, however, we will do not share specific individual information with a third-party.  

  * TAM operates several websites featuring its travel-related content and services. TAM may share personal information collected from users of its websites internally across these websites to better serve its users.

TAM has numerous products and services and therefore numerous email and promotion lists. In an effort to allow users to tailor their participation in TAM services and promotions, TAM provides users the ability to choose specific lists or products of interest and opt-out options are product and use/list specific. All email promotions sent from TAM provide an opt-out link at the bottom of the email pursuant to which users can opt-out of specific products and promotions. If you receive one of these emails and wish to unsubscribe please follow the instructions given in each email or contact [support@travelpulse.com](mailto:support@travelpulse.com).

From time to time we may use  customer information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our Privacy Policy. If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes to our website.

**Sharing of Information Collected With Third Parties**

In general, TAM does not rent, sell, or share personal information about you with other people or nonaffiliated companies except to provide products or services you have requested, when we have your permission, or under the following circumstances: 

  * We may provide personal information about our users to trusted partners and vendors who work on behalf of or with TAM under confidentiality and similar agreements prohibiting such partiesï¿½ further use of the information. These companies may use your personal information to help TAM communicate with you about offers from TAM and our marketing partners. However, these companies do not have any independent right to use or share this information.  

  * When you register for an educational program, contest, or other promotion that is sponsored by a third party, the third party will be provided personally identifiable information unless otherwise posted in connection with the promotion.   

  * TAM may from time to time share personal information such as email addresses with trusted third parties who deliver content that is likely to be of interest to the user and subject to opt-out obligation on the part of such third party.  

  * We may share personal information where we have a good faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a judicial proceeding, a court order, or legal process served on TAM, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.  

  * We may share such information where we have a good faith belief that it is necessary in order to investigate (or assist in the investigation of), prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of TAM's terms of use, or as otherwise required by law.   

  * If TAM is acquired by or merged with another company, we will transfer information about you to this other company in connection with the acquisition or merger.

**Discussion Groups**

Email discussion groups are available for our users on some of our websites. Participants should be aware that information disclosed in these discussion lists is made available to all members and thus becomes public information. We suggest that you exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information in such discussion groups.

**Security**

This website takes commercially reasonable precautions to protect your personal information.  When we transfer and receive certain types of sensitive information such as credit card and payment information, we re-direct users to industry standard SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encrypted servers. As a result, sensitive data you submit to our website such as credit card and payment information is transmitted securely over the Internet.

**Disclaimers**

TAM is not responsible for any breach of security or for any actions of any third parties that receive the information. TAM also links to a wide variety of other sites and contains advertisements of third parties. We are not responsible for their privacy policies or how they treat information about their users.

**About Children's Privacy**

This TAM website is not intended for use by children and TAM does not knowingly collect information from children. You must be 18 years old to access or use this site.

**Update/Change Your Data**

To update your email address or change your email preferences please contact [support@travelpulse.com](mailto:support@travelpulse.com)

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

TAM reserves the right, at any time and without notice, to add to, change, update or modify this Privacy Policy, simply by posting such change, update or modification on the website.  Any such change, update or modification will be effective immediately upon positing on the website.  Users will be informed of changes to this Privacy Policy via the "updated as of" link on the TAM website. 

**What Else Should I Know About My Privacy When Online?**

The TAM websites contain many hyperlinks to other websites. The TAM website also contains advertisements of third parties. TAM is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such third party websites or advertisers. TAM does not share any of the individual personal information you provide TAM with the websites to which TAM links, except as stated elsewhere within this Privacy Policy, although TAM may share aggregate data with such websites (such as how many people use our Site). 

Please check with those third party sites to determine their privacy policy. When TAM embeds third party content into one of it's TAM web pages, TAM will use reasonable efforts to advise our users that they have exited an TAM operated website and are entering a third party controlled website. Customers/users should read and understand any privacy policy noted on all third party websites.

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example through email, discussion lists, or elsewhere - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. 

Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your personal information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online. 

**Your Consent To This Policy**

By using our website, you consent to the collection and use of information by TAM as specified in this policy.  Please also note that your use of the website is governed by the TAM Terms and Conditions. If you do not agree to the terms of the Privacy Policy or the Terms and Conditions, please do not use the website, products and/or services. 

Please send any questions about TAM's Privacy Policy to [support@travelpulse.com](mailto:support@travelpulse.com)
